So tut's method tells you how to lay out the nodes of a planar graph in a plane so
Tufte的方法告诉你如何 给平面上的图节点布局
that the edges don't cross.
使得那些边不会交叉
If you don't have a planar graph, if you have an arbitrary graph, you need to use
如果你没有平面图 只有随机的图
a more specific methods to lay out a graph so that it could be easily visualized.
要用更有针对性的方法来布局 这样才能方便地可视化
So as we saw in the last set of slides tut's method for laying out a planar graph
正如之前的演示中 Tufte的平面图布局方法
places each node at a position that's the average of it's neighboring nodes.
将每个点放在 它的邻居的平均位置上
And so each of the nodes is applying a force to the current nodes position and
这样每个点就给当前的 点的位置施加一个力
so that's an example of a force directed layout.
这是力驱动布局的一个例子
Then there's quite a few different force directed layouts,
还有好多种力驱动布局的方式
a popular one is called Gem and that's what was used to layout this example.
其中宝石布局很流行 这就是本例中布局的方式
This is a interaction graph between yeast proteins,
这张图表示了酵母 蛋白质的互作用关系
there is about 1500 yeast proteins and about 2000 interactions and so the yeast
大约有1500个酵母蛋白质 和2000个互作用关系
proteins are indicated by nodes and the interactions are indicated by edges.
酵母蛋白质用节点表示 互作用关系用边表示
So in the GEM algorithm for forced directed layout,
在力驱动布局的GEM算法中
we're simulating the force of a spring system.
我们模拟一个弹簧系统的力
So each edge between two nodes corresponds to a spring, and
这样连接两个节点 的边对应一个弹簧
that spring has a rust length if the nodes are farther than that rest length and
如果弹簧比静止长度要长 那么它会有一个拉伸长度
they'll be attracted to each other.
而此时节点之间也会相互吸引
If they're closer than that rest length then they'll be repelling each other.
如果它们比静止长度要短 那么节点就会互相排斥
And also, if you have high degree nodes, if you have a node with a lot of
而且如果你有多级的节点 如果你有一个邻居很多的节点
neighbors, then Jim will make that rest length of the springs
那GEM会把弹簧的 静止长度延长
larger to try to push away those neighbors since there are so
以此把邻居推开 因为这些邻居节点有很多
many of those neighbors sharing an edge with that high degree node.
与那个多级数节点 共用一条边
There's also a repulsion
在节点之间还有一种排斥作用
between nodes even if there are not connected by a spring so that
虽然他们并没有被弹簧连起来
nodes don't end up on top of each other even if they're not connected by an edge.
就是为了使节点不叠加在一起 即使它们并不由一条边连接
And that repulsion force is basically equal to one over the distance
这种排斥力基本相当于 两点之间距离的倒数
between the node, between any two nodes.
存在于任何两个点之间
And then finally all the nodes experience a force of gravity towards the center
最后所有节点都会受到一种
of the graft to keep things from wandering too far away.
朝向图中心的引力 以使节点不要飘离太远
And a small random perturbation force just to make sure
还有一个很小的随机扰动力
that nodes take unique positions.
来保证节点的位置是唯一的
As we talk about the layout of graphs, by placing nodes,
在我们讨论以放置节点 来进行图布局的时候
it's good to think of the centrality of nodes.
如果能考虑节点的 中心性是很好的
And centralities are ways of analyzing
中心性是一种分析
you know where a node should be positioned in a layout.
节点应该放置在布局中 的哪个位置的方法
Should it be more central or should it be on the periphery here?
是应该放在更中间还是更边缘
So these nodes that are blue in color are central nodes.
这些蓝色节点是中心节点
These nodes that are red in color are non-central nodes.
红色节点是非中心节点
There's many different centrality metrics.
有很多种度量中心性的方式
Ways of measuring how central a node should be in a layout.
很多种测量中心节点 应该如何布局的方法
Node degree is a simple method where you just count the number of edges
节点度数是一种简单手法 只要计算一个节点拥有的
that a node has.
边的数量
And so nodes with high degree should be placed towards the center and
这样高度数的节点 应该放在中间
nodes with low degree might appear on the boundary.
低度数的节点可能会在边上
Page rank is a kind of centrality measure which Google uses to find popular
网叶排序（Page Rank） 也是一种中心性测量方法 Google用来查找
webpages by basically counting the number of incoming links from other webpages.
受欢迎的网页  方法大概是计算 其他页面到此页面的链接数
Another is based on the isolation metric.
另一种方法基于隔离度
You can think of the distance between nodes.
你可以把它想成 节点之间的距离
For example this green node here
例如这里的绿色点
to this red node has three edges between that, so it's distance would be three.
需要经过三条边到达红色点 那么距离就是三
It's the length of the shortest number or
距离指的是从 一个点到另一个点
edges to get from one node to another node is the distance.
所需要经过的 边的数量的最小值
The isolation matrix basically adds up
而隔离矩阵基本就是 表示的是将从一个点
the distance from a given node to all the other nodes in the graph.
到图上其他点的距离加起来
And if I add those up then I'll get a smaller result for
如果把它们相加 那么对离图中心较近的点而言
nodes towards the center of this graph.
结果就会比较小
And a larger result to nodes in the periphery of this graph,
而对处在图的边缘的点而言
in this particular layout.
在这种布局中 结果就会比较大
And so you can think of closeness centrality as basically the inverse of
你可以把亲近中心性看作
that isolation metric.
隔离度的倒数
So that nodes with high closeness centrality would have low isolation
这样邻近中心性高的点
metric.
隔离度就比较低
And you can also think of graph centrality, which is like the isolation
你也可以把图的中心性 看作隔离度
metric except I'm not taking the distance to all the nodes and adding them up.
只是我没有取所有节点的距离 然后把它们相加而已
I'm taking the distance between the node and the farthest node away from it, and
我取了节点和离它最远的 节点之间的距离
one over that gives me what's called the graph centrality.
它的倒数被叫做图的中心性值
And finally, there's between the centrality.
最后还有居间中心性
Between the centrality basically looks at every pair of nodes,
居间中心性指的是对任一对结点
and finds the shortest path between that pair of nodes.
找到这对节点之间的最短路径
If I take the shortest paths between any node and any other node, all
如果我找到任意节点和 另外一个节点之间的最短路径
of those shortest paths, how many of those shortest paths go through a given node?
然后统计经过一个特定的点的 所有最短路径
That tells me the betweenness centrality of that node.
这就是这个节点的居间中心性值
And so, if I take every shortest path between every node and every other node.
如果我选择每一个节点 和另一个节点之间最短路径
Those shortest paths will likely go through these central nodes more than they
这些最短路径更有可能 经过这些中心节点
will go through these peripheral nodes.
而不是边缘节点
And so that's what we have plotted here is nodes plotted based
所以我们在这里画出的是
on their betweenness centrality.
基于居间中心性的节点图
How many of the shortest paths between any two nodes go through each of these nodes.
任意两个点之间的最短路径 会经过哪些点呢?
It's high for these nodes that are blue in color and
蓝色的点值比较高
low for these nodes that are red in color.
红色的点值比较低
And you can also compute that for
你还可以以此对边进行统计
an edge, how many shortest paths go through an edge?
有多少最短路径经过某条边?
So, we can use use that between the centrality or
这样我们就可以用居间中心性
any of these centrality metrics to simplify a graph.
或者其他中心性度量 来简化一张图
And so, for example, if I compute the between the centrality of edges
例如 如果我计算 这个酵母蛋白质网络的
of my network of yeast proteins.
边的居间中心性
Edges that have low between the centrality,
居间中心性较低的边
have few shortest paths going through them.
经过他们的最短路径比较少
And edges with high between the centrality have a lot of edges going through them.
居间中心性较高的边 有很多边经过它们
And so a lot of shortest paths going through them.
所以有很多最短路径经过它们
And so if I remove edges that have few shortest paths going through them
那么如果我删除 有较少最短路径经过的边
you might think the impact would be less than if I have a lot of shortest paths
你会认为它的影响少于 删除有较多最短路径
going through that edge.
经过的边
So I've plotted the between the centrality of edges here, and I basically
这里是我根据边的居间中心性的 而作的绘图
removed the lowest between the centrality, the ones that are very dark blue and
然后删掉了居间中心性最低的 也就是深蓝色的边
left the highest between the centrality edges, the ones that are in red here.
留下了居间中心性最高的 也就是红色的边
And I've not removed any edge if it creates a disconnected graph.
如果去掉某条边会使图经不联通 我就没有去掉那些边
So the result is a graph that
这样的结果是
has as many edges as it has nodes, about 1500 edges and 1500 nodes.
图上的点和边一样多 大约1500条边和1500个点
So I guess something like a tree that's minimally connected,
我猜这像一个最少连通的树
but have retained the high between the centrality edges.
但是它保留了 居间中心性较高的边
And removed the lowest
而去掉了居间中心性较低的边
And so what's left is kind of the communications backbone,
这样余下的就是通讯主干
the most often used edges when I'm finding the shortest path between any two nodes.
也就是在寻找任意两个点 之间最短路径时最常用的边
And that simplifies the layout.
这就简化了布局
Now I've got fewer edges in order to compute
那么当我使用同样的 GEM布局图 即力驱动布局图
spring distances when I use the same gem layout, force-directed layout for
来计算弹簧距离时 右图中需要计算的边减少了
this graph on the right than I'm using for this graph on the left.
而左图中比较多
The nodes spread out more because I've got fewer springs.
右图中节点布局更分散 因为弹簧更少了
And the nodes are freer to move around to unique places.
而节点会更加自由的 移动到唯一的位置
And you can visually see the relationship between nodes better in this layout
在视觉上可以更好地看出 这种布局中节点的关系
than in this layout.
比原来的要好
You're also looking at fewer edges,
你也可以看出这里的边比较少
so you could always add back in the edges as necessary,
可以随时把必要的边加上去
to add back in those low between the centrality edges to see a more complete
可以加上那些 居间中心性比较低的边
view of this graph, but the nodes would still be positioned better than they are.
以此看到更完全的图 但此时的布局还是比原来要好
When you try to compute the layout using all of those edges.
当你试图用所有的边 来计算布局时
So there's other techniques for laying out graphs.
还有其他的方法用来给图布局
Here's an example technique called edge bundles where we just put all of the nodes
本例中的技术叫做边束 我们把所有节点放在一个圈内
in a ring and we make a circle, a radial layout of nodes and then we draw the edges
画个圆圈 节点按经向分布 然后在圈内画边
in the region inside this disk surrounded by this circle of nodes.
并被节点围成的圈所包围
And we can start to group edges together
这样我们就可以把边 束成一束
if we have some way of measuring the similarity of edges.
如果我们有方法来 判断边之间的相似性
We can create basically wire bundles called edge bundles that simplify
我们就可建立线束 这就叫做边束
the visualization of this graph.
它可以简化该图的可视化表示
In this case, these are emails that were part of the litigation for
本例是一个叫做Enron的公司 在2001年的诉讼案里
a company called Enron between 132 employees back in 2001.
132名员工之间的电子邮件
And here's a couple different layouts.
这里有几种不同的布局
This is a force directed layout of these node positions and
这是一种基于节点位置的 力驱动布局
then instead of having the edges, just go straight line.
而不是直接把边画成直线
Connecting each node we've tried to bundle the edges together so
把每个节点连起来以后 我们尝试着把边束起来
you can kind of see main communication pathways in these representations.
这样你就可以看到 在这些表示中主要的通讯线路
How do you find two edges to be similar or
你怎样得知两条边是相似
not similar to each other so that you can bundle them?
还是不相似 以此将它们束在一起呢？
Well this, for that task it's useful to form communities
对于这个任务而言 有效的方法是创建群落
to try to cluster nodes together in communities that are sharing
把那些共享有相似行为的边和 有相似边连接的点
similar edge behaviors, similar edge connections.
聚合起来
And so in order to find communities we can remove edges in order of decreasing
这样为了找到群落 可以根据中心性 或居间中心性的由大到小的顺序来去边
centrality, or decreasing between the centrality, which is what we used.
我们使用了后者
So instead of removing the low centrality edges like we did for
在之前的节点布局中 我们先移除中心性较低的边
node layout before, now we're removing high centrality edges.
与其不同 在这里 我们先移除中心性较高的边
So now we're moving the edges that are part of the main communication pathways.
现在我们移除一些边 是主要通信线路的一部分
What that does is that disconnects a graph and it isolates nodes.
这会让图变得不连通 产生一些孤立节点
It isolates nodes in clumps and
孤立的节点会聚集成团
those clumps form clusters that form communities.
而这些团形成聚合 进一步形成群落
So you can think of a community of nodes communicating through
这样你可以把 群落里的节点想成
another community of node, across a high between the centrality edge, and so
它们从具有高居间中心性的边 与另外的群落通讯
by removing our edges from the highest between the centrality to the lowest
这样当我们依次去掉 居间中心性较高到较低的边时
centrality edges, we're creating a hierarchy of these communities.
我们就为这些群落 划分了层级关系
As we remove those edges, we can create nodes that represent where those edges
删除边时可以创建节点来表示 这些边所连接的群落
connected communities to and so we can use the resulting communities to figure out
这样就可以用这些群落 来弄清楚应该以什么顺序
the order in which to lay our vertices on the periphery on this circle.
把这些节点布置在圆的边缘上
And then by merging those clumps together we can place vertices in the interior
再通过把这些集团聚合在一起 我们可以把节点放在内部
to denote higher level communities.
来表示更高级的群落
These are called community notes, they're not part of the original graph.
这叫群落节点 他们不是原本的图的一部分
They're just used to represent communities,
只是用来表示群落而已
to represent mergings of clumps of nodes.
来表示节点集团的聚合
And so here's some examples of Edge Bundle Communities.
这里有一些边束群落的例子
In this case we took every football game between colleges in the United States.
本例中我们看到 美国所有大学之间的橄榄球赛
University of Illinois is one of these colleges.
伊利诺伊大学是其中的一所
And by just taking, any time any college played another college,
参与之后 任意时间任一学校 会与另一所学校的对决
we would connect that with an edge and by looking at the final graph, removing
我们可以用一条边来表示 看最后的绘图
the high between the centrality edges, they started to isolate communities and
把具有高居间中心性的边移除 他们就会开始分化出群落
we were able to figure out a layout that represented these low-level communities.
而我们就能找出一个布局 来表示这些低层次的群落
We basically rediscovered the conferences.
这几乎就像重新发现了 校际间的球赛联盟
And so, just by looking at all the games played between, games of
所以通过查看所有举行的比赛
football played between one university and another in the US we were able to discover
也就是美国一个学校与另一学校的橄榄球赛 我们就可以发现
the conferences that organized the games between colleges in the US.
美国大学之间 比赛的联盟关系
And then we can use that community structure to figure out an edge metric.
然后就可以运用这种群落结构 来弄清楚边的关系
So, edges from one section of the community
所以一个群落中一区域的边和 另一区域的边
to another section of a community can then be clumped together and form these edge
可以缩并起来形成边束
bundles by basically attracting them to these edge node positions.
方法是把它们吸引到 边的节点位置上
So here's an example of the actual communities from Enron, and
这里的例子表示了Enron的实际群落
here's the communities we discovered.
我们所发现的群落
These don't lie in the same position as the rest of these.
这些和这里的其余部分 不在同一个位置上
For example here's where the president of Enron is and
例如这是Enron主席
he's listed here in the CEO section here.
他被列在这里的CEO区域
But we found the same actual communities were discovered
我们也发现了同样的这个群落
by basically removing high between the centrology edges from the graph of
通过在由员工 发邮件关系组成的图中
all emails from one employee to another ended up revealing these communities.
去除高居间中心性的边 然后得到这些群落
And as we'll see later it's useful to be able to filter out and
我们之后会看到 过滤和关注互动细节
look at details interactively in these edge bundle examples or
在边束的案例或任何 大型数据集中 都是非常有用的
in any large data set, so we can click for example on the CEO of Enron, Kenneth Lay.
我们可以点击 比如说 Enron的CEO Kenneth Lay
And see all the email that was sent in this data set to all the other employees,
来查看所有传给其他员工
to all the other communities.
或者其他群落的电子邮件
For example I can click on Illinois, and
再比如我可以点击 伊利诺伊大学
I can see all the other Big 10 conference games that it had, but
就可以看到它在十大联盟内 参与的其他联盟球赛
I can also see the games it had to other places outside of its conference.
但也可以看到它在联盟之外 参加的球赛
So there's a variety of methods that we've just seen to visualize graphs.
我们刚才看到的 可视化图的方法有很多
Not necessarily planar graphs, but any graph.
并不一定是平面图 可以是任何图
Social networks and other graphs.
社交网络或者其他的图
And they're based largely on analyses that are enabled by that centrality,
它们都大部分基于中心性分析
the definition of some kind of centrality of the nodes.
某种对节点做出的 中心性的定义
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community